Hi Guys welcome back.
So just as we saw the activity of developing project charter in the last video in this video we are
going to talk about developing the project management plan and this is not just one document and we
can say that project management creation requires you to create multiple documents.
Now having said that there is project management plan of project charter.
It's all about your organizational process assets.
All companies have their own templates and tools like project management tool or Jeta software.
There are a lot of tools in the market used by a variety of companies across industries so if you are
using something like that that could make your life easier for example it may have a section for Bluebeard's
where you just have to enter the data and it will give you the output in the form of a template of a
report which can be used for project management plan.
And it also happens at a predefined stage so usually happens at the beginning after project charter
has been developed.
So once you have that document you need to work on your project management plan.
This will require to know your details about your resourcing timelines cost and those kind of details
will go into it along with the scoop and many other details.
So just as for last activity business case was in part for project charter here we have project charter
as input and along with an alignment of factors organizational process assets and other output other
output could be any other document which is relevant to the project and was produced doing earlier stages
of the project so it could be anything.
And sometimes there may not be anything.
So if you don't have say you only have a project charter document Don't worry that's OK.
You are still doing good.
And then we have these techniques which are again same because ultimately the nature of the job remains
the same.
And the output is project management plan and just as project charter was being used for many other
activities.
Project management plan also contributes a lot.
But first let's see some of these common components of a project management plan.
So these could be you know and as I was talking about multiple activities these could drip form the
various component of our project management plan so it could be I scored a management plan requirement
management plan and all these you know various plans here.
Then you can have the baselines which is the school baseline timeline schedule cost baselining is basically
the signed an approved version so let's say you started with 100000 USD project but then you went to
the stakeholders and they said they can not give you more than 75 k.
You work with the development team and came up with the estimates within that.
So 75 K will be approved and signed off limit and this is the baseline.
So not just in terms of money baseline simply means the signed off and approved so if you are talking
about the budget it is that if you're talking about the time line the baseline will mean the finalized
timeline.
That's it.
And then we will have additional documents like the change management plan configuration management
plan and project lifecycle and management views exactly.
So these are very common components especially at the top subsidiary management plans and you need to
review and remember all projects are unique in some ways.
For each project when you start to work on it you need to start from scratch even if youre using the
template.
So which means that you need to see what information is needed for that project and it could be seen.
But in many cases it could be different.
So if some sections some information wasn't there in Somalia or project it doesn't mean that you don't
need it here.
Also for example procurement management plan.
Now this would be part of subsidiary management plans.
So I'm hoping that you are using your Trimbach and I have used bookstores in a lot of days for months
even if you are at some earlier version.
I don't know but I think you should be OK.
So I'm coming back to this so let's say a procurement management plan it has to or if you are dealing
with procurement for this project even if it wasn't there in some earlier project.
So you have to remember that every project is unique and you have to review the required details which
are needed for a particular project.
And you can find a lot of templates online.
In fact p.m.-I website is a very good source.
There are free and premium templates there so let's say you are a new project manager who's looking
to get a project management plan.
You can simply visit the BMI website.
Let me show you.
So I am at BMI Dot who are learning tools and techniques you can simply Google DPMI templates a good
p.m.-I project management template and it will take you here so you can see that we have different menu
options here.
The left side will simply click on View templates on the project management dot com.
So when we click that it will take us to another site and here we have all these templates which are
required for deliverables.
Project plans presentations checklist within project plan.
There are certain templates which are paid.
In that case you will see.
You will need to see if you can buy it and they are also free plans.
And one more thing.
Basically when you click on a particular project plan it will give you all these various versions of
this Tuckerman so I must project 2001 is the US version of the M.S. project which is the software used
for project management.
This is Microsoft product.
But if you are using some model then you will have to look at alternate ways.
But in that case let's see if you are using Jira.
I'm sure they will provide something but you can always use these templates for reference purposes and
then you can modify them.
So that's it for now.
Thank you.